{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "When acceleration is _______, velocity of a particle is constant.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "zero",
        "b": "Maximum",
        "c": "none of the above",
        "d": "constant but non zero"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In closed loop control system, with positive value of feedback gain the overall gain of the system will...",
      "answers": {
        "a": "decrease",
        "b": "Increase",
        "c": "Be unaffected",
        "d": "Any of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A simple Mass Spring Damper System having natural frequency wn.If the spring stiffness is halved and mass is doubled,what will be its natural frequency?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2wn",
        "b": "wn/2",
        "c": "4wn",
        "d": "8wn"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A block whose mass is 4kg is fastened with a spring constant k=64N/m.The block is pulled from its equilibrium position on a frictionless surface and released. The period of the resulting motion is in seconds is..",
      "answers": {
        "a": "&#960;/2",
        "b": "2&#960;",
        "c": "&#960;/4",
        "d": "&#960;"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The natural frequency of a mass spring damper system is wn.The natural frequency of this system in the moon will be..",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.408wn",
        "b": "0.204wn",
        "c": "1.167wn",
        "d": "wn"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The time period of a mass spring damper system depends on,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Mass of the block",
        "b": "Spring Constant",
        "c": "Both",
        "d": "none"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The time period of a mass suspended from a spring is 'T'.If the spring is cut into 4 equal parts and same mass is suspended from one of the parts,then the new time period will be,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "T",
        "b": "2T",
        "c": "T/4",
        "d": "T/2"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "When a system is vibrating in a normal mode,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "All masses move with the same Amplitude and same Frequency",
        "b": "All masses move with the same Amplitude and different Frequency",
        "c": "All masses move with different Frequency but of same phase",
        "d": "All masses move with the same frequency and maintain a fixed phase relation"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A mass of 0.5 kg is suspended in a vertical plane by a spring having a stiffness coefficient of 300 N/m. The mass is displaced vertically downward from its static equilibrium position through a distance of 0.01m . Find the natural frequency of the sysytem.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "24.5Hz",
        "b": "31.6Hz",
        "c": "5.1Hz",
        "d": "3.9Hz"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "When acceleration is _______, velocity of a particle is constant.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Maximum",
        "b": "Zero",
        "c": "constant but not zero",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }






  ]
}
